[
    {
        "question": "Se biscop grete þone (<i>cyning</i>) #### — The bishop greets the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'grete', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "FILLER",
                "explanation": "1"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "þa biscopas geaf þone (<i>stan</i>) #### to þaem þegne — The bishops gave the stone to the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "stan",
        "explanation":"Here 'stan' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",        
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badanswer": "Wrong Answer 2",
                "explanation": "2"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen sloh þone (<i>biscop</i>) #### in tæm tune — the thane slew the bishop in the town",
        "correctAnswer": "biscop",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'sloh', so is in the singular accusative and thus takes no new ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "FILLER",
                "explanation": "3"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ond seo cwen grete þa (<i>biscop</i>) #### — The king and the queen greet the bishops",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'grete' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "FILLER",
                "explanation": "4"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning sloh þa (<i>þegen</i>) #### — The king slew the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'sloh' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "5"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen geaf þa (<i>gar</i>) #### to þaem cyninge — The thane gives the spears to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "garas",
        "explanation":"Here 'gar' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "6"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To þæm biscop geaf se cyning þa (<i>beag</i>) #### — The king gave rings to the bishop",
        "correctAnswer": "beagas",
        "explanation":"Here 'beag' is directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf' and is also plural, so it is in the plural accusative and thus takes the 'as' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "7"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To þæm (<i>cyning</i>) #### se biscop geaf beag — To the king, the bishop gives a ring",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninge",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending.",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "8"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se þegen ferþ to þæm (<i>biscop</i>) #### mid wordum fram þæm cyning — The thane goes to the bishop with words from the king",
        "correctAnswer": "biscope",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferþ', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "9"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se biscop ferde fram þæm (<i>þegen</i>) #### to þæm cyning — The bishop went from the thane to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "þegne",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "10"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "On þis daeg, Æðelred cyning ferde to þæm (<i>tun</i>) #### mid broðor— On this day, King Ethelred went to the town his brother",
        "correctAnswer": "tune",
        "explanation":"Here 'tun' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the singular dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "11"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ferþ to þæm (<i>beorg</i>) #### — The king goes to the mountains",
        "correctAnswer": "beorgum",
        "explanation":"Here 'beorg' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferþ', so it is in the plural dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "12"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Wærferhþ biscop ferde to þæm (<i>biscop</i>) #### in Lundene ond Wiltunscire — Bishop Warfehth went to the bishops of London and Wiltshire",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopum",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'ferde', so it is in the plural dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "13"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se geaf þa garas to þæm (<i>þegen</i>) #### — He gave the spears to the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnum",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'geaf', so it is in the plural dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "Wrong Answer 1",
                "explanation": "14"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "þa biscopas came fram þæm (<i>tun</i>) #### hetum Londenum ond Readingum — The bishops came from the towns called London and Reading",
        "correctAnswer": "tunum",
        "explanation":"Here 'tun' is not directly receiving the action of the verb 'came', so it is in the plural dative and thus takes the 'e' ending",        
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badanswer": "Wrong Answer 3",
                "explanation": "15"
            }
        ]
    }
]



